<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorials on 3dasd</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorials on 3dasd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assembly</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/assembly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/assembly/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Build overview</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/build-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/build-overview/</guid><description>Build overview # This is an overview of the steps required for building your scanner. See the links below for the detailed instructions on every topic.
Electronics # You need to order two PCBs and a couple electronic components first. Then solder things together (pretty basic through-hole soldering only!). Once everything&amp;rsquo;s set up, you need to do a little calibration and assemble a few cables.
See Electronics for all the details.</description></item><item><title>Electronics</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/electronics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/electronics/</guid><description>Electronics # This page walks you through obtaining and putting together all the electronics components required for building a 3dasd scanner.
Ordering everything # You need to get the following:
two PCBs (main and power supply) with a bunch of electronic components two sets of NEMA 17 stepper motors and A4988 drivers Garmin LIDAR-Lite v3 a Raspberry Pi Zero W an Arduino Nano a slip-ring a 12V 2A power supply wires for making the cables Getting the PCBs # You need to get two PCBs: the scanner and the scanner-power-supply.</description></item><item><title>Mechanics</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/mechanics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/mechanics/</guid><description>Mechanics # This page walks you through obtaining all the mechanical parts required for building a 3dasd scanner. Most of the chassis can be 3D-printed, but there are a few metal pieces that hold everything together.
The metal parts # You need a couple nuts and bolts and also some ball bearings and magnets. Here&amp;rsquo;s the shopping list:
Item Quantity M2 nut 3 M3 nut 10 M4 nut 13 M2 10 bolt 3 M3 6 bolt 2 M3 8 bolt 4 M3 12 bolt 4 M4 10 bolt 4 M4 16 bolt 1 M4 20 bolt 1 M4 25 bolt 3 M4 40 bolt 4 50x72x12 bearing 1 6x13x5 bearing 3 3x2 disk magnet 2 Understanding the dimensions</description></item><item><title>Software components</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/software/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Under the hood</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/under-the-hood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/under-the-hood/</guid><description>Under the hood # lidar-driver is the program running on the Arduino Nano. It is listening for commands on the serial (UART) interface and controls the LIDAR and the motors accordingly. lidar-client is the client running on the Raspberry Pi Zero that connects to lidar-driver. It&amp;rsquo;s a shell to send commands and also persists the points cloud results coming back from the driver. point-convert is a standalone application that converts from the asdp format of the driver to pcd or asc.</description></item><item><title>Usage</title><link>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3dasd.com/docs/tutorials/usage/</guid><description>Usage # When you power up the scanner from the 12V power supply it automatically connects to your WiFi network. You can connect to the scanner from your computer via SSH and launch a command line application where you can send commands to the scanner.
The point clouds taken by the scanner are saved on the scanner itself and can be downloaded to your computer via the same SSH connection.</description></item></channel></rss>